A murderer strikes on board the luxury Nile steamer Karnak –
and Hercule Poirot faces his most baffling case.
Death on the Nile is a mystery film directed by John Guillermin.
As Hercule Poirot enjoys a luxurious cruise down the Nile, a newlywed heiress is found
murdered on board and every elegant passenger becomes a prime suspect.
Hercule Poirot, played by Peter Ustinov.
Louise Bourget, played by Jane Birkin.
Linnet Ridgeway Doyle, played by Lois Chiles.
Marie Van Schuyler, played by Bette Davis.
Jacqueline de Bellefort, played by Mia Farrow.
James Ferguson, played by Jon Finch.
Death on the Nile is a 1978 British mystery film based on Agatha Christie's 1937 novel of
the same name, directed by John Guillermin and adapted by Anthony Shaffer.
The film features the Belgian detective Hercule Poirot, played by Peter Ustinov for the first time, plus an all-star supporting cast that
includes Maggie Smith, Angela Lansbury, Bette Davis, Mia Farrow, Jane Birkin, David Niven, George Kennedy, and Jack Warden.
The film is a standalone sequel to the 1974 film Murder on the Orient Express.
It takes place in Egypt in 1937, mostly on a period paddle steamer on the Nile.
Various famous Ancient Egyptian sights are featured in the film, such as the
Great Pyramids, the Sphinx, and temples at Abu Simbel and Karnak.
Death on the Nile won the Academy Award for Best
Costume Design at the 51st Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of egypt, based on novel or
book, paddleboat, pyramid, cruise.
The tone is mind_bending.